ILGWU. James Lipsig papers, 5780/082
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. James Lipsig papers
1921-1978.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Lipsig, James.
5780/082
18.5 cubic feet
18.5 linear feet
Records
Contains the records of James Lipsig, Assistant Executive Secretary of the ILGWU, as well as Treasurer of the ILGWU Campaign Committee from 1966 to 1976. Included are files on the Campaign Committee, Congressional redistricting, disability, displaced persons, equal employment opportunity, the Jewish Labor Committee, and Unity House. Meeting minutes include those of the Campaign Committee, Education Committee, Union Health Center Committee, and the Socialist Party USA's New York State Convention. Reports include those from local unions summarizing their responses on their Local Union Equal Opportunity Report to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. Also included are correspondence and applications relating to the ILGWU's Displaced Persons Project whereby the union sought admission of 400 individuals per the Displaced Persons Act of 1948. Lipsig's records also contain a draft manuscript of Gus Tyler's Organized Crime in America: A Book of Readings (University of Michigan, 1962) is also contained.
5492783
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
1993
EAD encoding:
Casey Westerman, 2003Randall Miles, 2008Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
After working as general counsel for the Textile Workers of America, James Lipsig served as Assistant Executive Secretary of the ILGWU for thirty years. Throughout his career, Lipsig also served as secretary of the Socialist Party of New York State, as board member of the Jewish Labor Committee, the National Sharecroppers' Fund and the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory, and as a consultant to the Workers Defense League. Born in New York City, Lipsig was a graduate of City College and Columbia University Law School. He died in New York City on December 18, 1976 at the age of 66.
Scope and Contents
Contains the records of James Lipsig, Assistant Executive Secretary of the ILGWU, as well as Treasurer of the ILGWU Campaign Committee from 1966 to 1976. Included are files on the Campaign Committee, Congressional redistricting, disability, displaced persons, equal employment opportunity, the Jewish Labor Committee, and Unity House. Meeting minutes include those of the Campaign Committee, Education Committee, Union Health Center Committee, and the Socialist Party USA's New York State Convention. Reports include those from local unions summarizing their responses on their Local Union Equal Opportunity Report to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. Also included are correspondence and applications relating to the ILGWU's Displaced Persons Project whereby the union sought admission of 400 individuals per the Displaced Persons Act of 1948. Lipsig's records also contain a draft manuscript of Gus Tyler's Organized Crime in America: A Book of Readings (University of Michigan, 1962) is also contained.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/126. ILGWU. James Lipsig papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; People with disabilities -- United States; Displaced workers -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- United States; Lipsig, James.; Lipsig, James.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5492783
- Series I. General Executive Board files, 1949-1978.
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GEB Grievance and Appeal Committee, 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU Campaign Committee [folder 1 of 3], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU Campaign Committee [folder 2 of 3], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ILGWU Campaign Committee [folder 3 of 3], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - GEB Constitution Revision Committee, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - GEB Convention Agreements Committee Minutes, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - GEB Education Committee Minutes and Reports [folder 1 of 5], 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - GEB Education Committee Minutes and Reports [folder 2 of 5], 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - GEB Education Committee Minutes and Reports [folder 3 of 5], 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - GEB Education Committee Minutes and Reports [folder 4 of 5], 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - GEB Education Committee Minutes and Reports [folder 5 of 5], 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - GEB Finance Committee Minutes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - GEB Health, Welfare and Death Benefit Funds Committee Reports and Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1951- 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - GEB Health, Welfare and Death Benefit Funds Committee Reports and Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1954- 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - GEB Jurisdiction Committee Reports, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - GEB Staff Retirement Fund Committee Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - GEB Special Sub-Committee Reports, 1952-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - GEB Union Health Center Committee Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - GEB Unity House Committee Reports, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Disability Benefits Materials, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Local Union Manager Meeting Minutes, 1949-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - GEB Meeting Reports to Dubinsky [folder 1 of 2], 1949-1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - GEB Meeting Reports to Dubinsky [folder 2 of 2], 1949-1958 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ILGWU Training Institute, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series II. General files, 1949-1976
  - Amott, Baker and Company Correspondence and Statistical Data Sheets, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annuities and Equitable Life Assurance Materials, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 1 of 3], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 2 of 3], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 3 of 3], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 1 of 4], 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 2 of 4], 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 3 of 4], 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Committee Minutes, Reports and Correspondence [folder 4 of 4], 1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 1 of 4], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 2 of 4], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 3 of 4], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 4 of 4], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 1 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 2 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 3 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 4 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 5 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 6 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 7 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 8 of 8], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 1 of 4], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 2 of 4], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 3 of 4], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 4 of 4], 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 1 of 5], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 2 of 5], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 3 of 5], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 4 of 5], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Committee Reports [folder 5 of 5], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 4], 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 4], 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 3 of 4], 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 4 of 4], 1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 5], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 5], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 3 of 5], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 4 of 5], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 5 of 5], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 4], 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 4], 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 3 of 4], 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 4 of 4], 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 2], 1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 2], 1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 3], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 3], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 3 of 3], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 1 of 2], 1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Committee Congressional Redistricting [folder 2 of 2], 1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - New York State Committee for Fair Representation [folder 1 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - New York State Committee for Fair Representation [folder 2 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - New York State Committee for Fair Representation [folder 3 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Remarks by Comptroller Beame to Local 1, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    October 25, 1973
  - Requests to the David Dubinsky Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - David Dubinksy Foundation Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1975 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - David Dubinsky Foundation Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Campaign Committee. Election Materials, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Committee. McGovern Campaign Materials, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Committee. McGovern Rally Materials, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Committee. University of Michigan Mailing List, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Political Department, ILGWU. Correspondence and Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Political Department, ILGWU. Correspondence and Reports, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Political Department, ILGWU. Correspondence and Reports, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Political Department, ILGWU. Election Materials, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Political Department, ILGWU. Election Materials, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Committee. Tyler Gus Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Committee Tyler Gus Book Distribution Responses, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Tyler, Gus. Correspondence, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Tyler, Gus. Correspondence, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Tyler, Gus. Correspondence, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Tyler, Gus. Mailings, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Tyler, Gus. Mailings, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Tyler, Gus. Radio and Television Appearances, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Tyler, Gus. Book Release Correspondence, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Tyler, Gus. Underworld [folder 1 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Tyler, Gus. Underworld [folder 2 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Tyler, Gus. Underworld [folder 3 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1948-1947 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1949-1956 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Local Transfer Requests and Complaints, 1958-1962 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Civil Rights Film Association Correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. General, 1949-1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. New Jersey, 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. New York [folder 1 of 4], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. New York [folder 2 of 4], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. New York [folder 3 of 4], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Disability Benefit Laws. New York [folder 4 of 4], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Changes in Disability Benefit Laws [folder 1 of 2], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Changes in Disability Benefit Laws [folder 2 of 2], 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Retirement and Reciprocity Retirement [folder 1 of 2], 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Retirement and Reciprocity Retirement [folder 2 of 2], 1953-1955 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 1 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 2 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 3 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondences and Questionnaires [folder 4 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 5 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 6 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence and Questionnaires [folder 7 of 7], 1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Displaced Persons Project Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Displaced Persons Correspondence (Outside of New York), 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Education Department, ILGWU, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 1-99 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 1-99 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 100-199 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 199-200 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 200-299 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 200-299 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 300-399 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 300-399 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 400-499 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 400-499 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 500-599 [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Locals 500-599 [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports. Awaiting Replies, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Report Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Report Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Grouped Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Reports from Joint Boards and District Councils, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Referral Unions [folder 1 of 3], 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Referral Unions [folder 2 of 3], 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Referral Unions [folder 3 of 3], 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - ILGWU 1965 Election Candidate Materials [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU 1965 Election Candidate Materials [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Federation of Union Representatives. Correspondence, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Federation of Union Representatives. Reports, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Federation of Union Representatives. Court of Appeals Brief, 1964-1968 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Federation of Union Representatives. Memos and Newsletters, 1961-1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Federation of Union Representatives. Department Transfer Materials, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 7)